# Samuel Haile

# Software Developer + Business Systems Analyst

samishken@gmail.com (267) 934-0203

Over 10 years of experience in Financial Services, and a passion for leveraging technology to develop and drive transformation. Dedicated to tackling new technologies and methods to expand and apply expertise to challenging problems. Quickly able to learn and master new technologies with proven success working in both a team and self-directed setting.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages & Frameworks: Ruby on Rails | Selenium-webdriver | JavaScript | React | Ember | Node |

Express | HTML | CSS

Management & Deployment: Git | GitHub | Heroku | Command Line

Databases: SQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | SQLite

Methodologies: Object Oriented Programming | MVC Pattern | Test-Driven Development | Responsive Design

| Authentication | User Stories | ERDs | Wireframing | Agile Development/Scrum

Knowledgeable: Python | AWS solution architecture | PostgreSQL online bootcamp certified

Automation Tests: RSpec framework with Capybara | Selenium-webdriver

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Developer, 21PSTEM, Conshohocken, PA

May 2018 - February 2019

<u>Description</u>: PARLO Tracker is a robust interactive online assessment management system (AMS) which is used to manage progressive evidence of student mastery of Student Learning Outcomes, Competencies, or similar learning benchmarks. PARLO Tracker also enables parents, students and administrators to monitor student progress toward mastery of strategic content.

Environment: Ruby on Rails, Capybara with RSpec, SQLite, Selenium-webdriver, HTML5, CSS3, Github

### Responsibilities:

- ♦ Analyzing the business and functional requirements and developed Test Scenarios and Test Cases.
- ♦ Developed Automation Test scripts using RSpec testing frame with Capybara library for integration testing and for regression test suit.
- ◆ Created yml and user action support files to execute RSpec test scripts.
- ♦ Familiar with rails MVC frame work on Ruby programming language.
- ◆ Used Ruby Gems and methods to develop automation test scripts.
- ◆ Executed existing automation script on Selenium-webdriver.
- ◆ Performed Manual Testing as part of every Iteration.
- ♦ Merge the automations scripts with source code by using Githab.
- ◆ Performed UAT testing on each deployment.
- ♦ Prepared Traceability Matrix to review the requirements and Test Case coverage.♦ Performed the both automation and manual testing to cover Traceability Matrix.
- ♦ Enforced existing process guidelines; drive new processes, guidelines, team rules, and best practices.
- ◆ Added new features to give 21PSTEM the ability to switch the software from US to Non US.

- ◆ Added Strong Parameters.
- ♦ Fixed all Deprecation Warnings while updating the software Rails 3.0 to Rails 4.0.
- ♦ Successfully updated the software from Rails 3.0 to Rails 4.0.
- ♦ Worked with product owners to understand desired application capabilities and testing scenarios.
- ♦ Documented new and changed software using well placed comments and guides.
- ♦ Collaborated with other technology teams to ensure integrated end-to-end design and integration.
- ♦ Enforced existing process guidelines; drive new processes, guidelines, team rules, and best practices.

## General Assembly, Washington, DC

January 2018 - May 2018

- ♦ Invested 500 hours over 12 weeks learning and practicing full-stack web development fundamentals including React, Node JS, Express, MongoDB, JavaScript and Ruby on Rails.
- ♦ Created a portfolio of projects individually and collaborative projects including:
  - ERRFII: Application uses React JS, Chart JS and Google Maps API all together to show Visual data to clients who are interested in international investing.
  - esGApe: This app was created to help General Assembly students and instructors share their experience about restaurants and bars around the school. It is a MERN stack application.
  - Auto Dealer: This application helps a car dealer to monitor and update it's inventory.
    Created using MongoDB/Mongoose, Express.js, Handlebars.js and Node.js with the Google Places API.
  - Super-bowl Trivia: This project was to develop a responsive single page front end UI using JavaScript. I created an interactive app for NFL fans and newcomers to test their knowledge about the Super-bowl

# Business Systems Analyst, JPMorgan Chase & Co, Newark, DE

December 2015 - November 2017

- ♦ Collaborated with IT teams to design and implement new solutions, maximize operating efficiencies and reduce cost
- ♦ Designed, implemented and maintained Genesys Call Routing configuration, and business routing logic and strategies for multiple businesses.
- ♦ Provided first level support on priority issues escalation.

### Supervisor, Net Asset Value Analyst, BNY Mellon, Wilmington, DE

March 2006 - December 2015

- ♦ Served as liaison between the Portfolio Management Group, Global Client Group, Operations and Technology to ensure the accuracy of performance/NAV calculations and attribution related issues.
- ♦ Crated and run quarterly performance metrics reports.

Production Analyst, AHP Settlement Trust, Philadelphia, PA

March 2002 - March 2006

♦ Assisted with general administrative support within IT Department.

#### **EDUCATION**

Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA — Bachelor's Degree

**September 2000 - May 2003** 

B.A. in Management Information Systems and Accounting.